<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiago&#39;s 🏡</title>
    <link>https://xroot.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tiago&#39;s 🏡</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 22:55:17 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xroot.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Movie Recommendation 📹 The Report</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/movie-the-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 22:55:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/movie-the-report/</guid>
      <description>The Report - 2019
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks 🚫 Tools &amp; Productivity ✅</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/life-after-socials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 13:33:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/life-after-socials/</guid>
      <description>Recently I decided it was time to not only a break but instead a full departure from social networks. This is a process that started years ago when I first got rid of other services but it was only completed when the last standing social network profile came to an end:
The time has come for my last social network presence (Twitter) to come to an end.
Stay safe out there and feel free to reach out to me at tiago @3CORESec ✉️</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Guardduty vs IDS</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/guardduty-vs-ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 13:52:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/guardduty-vs-ids/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an AWS Blog post titled New third-party test compares Amazon GuardDuty to network intrusion detection systems where the author links to a white paper written by, as the title suggest, a third party.
The intent of their article is to provide an unbiased analyses of the capabilities of AWS GuardDuty when compared with &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; network intrusion detection systems. I do not, however, believe this objective was reached, and I want to highlight a few points about it in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dualcomm ETAP 2003</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/dualcomm-etap-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 13:55:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/dualcomm-etap-2003/</guid>
      <description>The Dualcomm ETAP-2003 is a pretty nifty little device. Because I could not find any images of them before I purchased mine, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a few photos I took:
       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3CORESec</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/3coresec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/3coresec/</guid>
      <description>3CORESec, which got its name from the &amp;ldquo;three cores&amp;rdquo; that go into our business goals (truth, trust &amp;amp; transparency) is a boutique information security company dedicated to creating managed detection security platforms, products and services.
Officially opened in 2019, 3CORESec, or 3CS for short, started with the idea of making robust information security products more easily accessible as well as developing these products with real-world, enterprise-ready capabilities. With so many products and services built under a lab environment, it&amp;rsquo;s a shame how many good ideas are lost when they face the demanding requirements of enterprises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, welcome! 👋🏽
xroot.org is the personal homepage of Tiago Faria (that&amp;rsquo;s me).
I started the website back in 2006 to run a Wordpress blog and in its 15 years of existence I&amp;rsquo;ve changed content and purpose so many times it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep track. With no more presence in social networks, this will be the place I get to call online home.
$ cat about.txt I have around 1000 hobbies even though I only get to put in practice a handful of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Best way to reach me is by using my first name @ the domain you&amp;rsquo;re visiting now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
