<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tiago&#39;s 🏡</title>
    <link>https://xroot.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tiago&#39;s 🏡</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:55:17 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xroot.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Economics</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/twitter-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:55:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/twitter-economics/</guid>
      <description>Oppose - genuinely - fighting the ridiculously large bot/spam network. Ad/Marketing model: charge for followers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telegram and crypto ...</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/telegram-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 23:43:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/telegram-crypto/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest countersenses I&amp;rsquo;ve seen is crypto people promoting and using Telegram &amp;hellip;
And no, it has nothing to do with MTProto.
#CryptoMeansCryptography</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series Recommendation 📺 Halt and Catch Fire</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/series-hcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 06:59:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/series-hcf/</guid>
      <description>Halt and Catch Fire - 2014
  The first two seasons of this show are, simply put, amazing!
I feel the show took quite a different direction in S03 (technology was no longer the subject pushing the entire show forward). There&amp;rsquo;s a shift towards personal relationships and technology became something that was part of the show, no longer the main subject of it.
By the show finale it definitely felt darker and lost a lot of that feel good aspect that we would get out of watching the protagonists run a modem bank, buying second-hand servers or hearing a dial-up connection being established.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you&#39;re a SaaS provider charging a premium for SAML/SSO ...</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/idiot-saas-saml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 22:40:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/idiot-saas-saml/</guid>
      <description>Fuck off!
Putting authentication options at the highest possible plan is just an idiot move, no other way around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 20th birthday Xbox 💚</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/xbox-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 15:42:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/xbox-20/</guid>
      <description>We have not always seen eye to eye Xbox, but today is your day.
 Happy 20th birthday!
Xbox&amp;rsquo;s 20th birthday is a good reminder of the many stories, sleepless nights, friendships and rage quits that I&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to experience. From the first time I saw Gears of War (and played for 18 hours straight) to learning about XBMC (that is still a reference in open-source to this day) and being able to have a multimedia player that I could FTP my content to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series Recommendation 📺 Glória</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/series-gloria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 23:22:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/series-gloria/</guid>
      <description>Glória - 2021
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailscale - VPN done RIGHT!</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/tailscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 22:59:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/tailscale/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wrote about how I don’t feel confident using Canonical’s Landscape and how my particular use case, where Landscape was my only means of accessing certain servers after they were deployed, made for an interesting challenge on how to tackle this self imposed limitation while keeping our operational goals in place.
When designing a solution to address connectivity to remote/edge computers obviously our good old VPN will be the first go-to tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explain the nonsense of the stock market with just two stocks 📉</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/market-aapl-estc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 22:40:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/market-aapl-estc/</guid>
      <description>Much can be said about evaluations and how the market perceives a certain company. That being said, there is absolutely nothing that justifies or explains something like this:
 That’s it. That’s the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YT Recommendation 👨🏻‍💻 Dark Space</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/yt-darkspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 21:18:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/yt-darkspace/</guid>
      <description>Dark Space
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series Recommendation 📺 The The Billion Dollar Code</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/series-billion-dollar-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 23:22:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/series-billion-dollar-code/</guid>
      <description>The Billion Dollar Code - 2021
  Being proud and willing to defend the Chaos Computer Club is just the cherry on top of the cake that is this amazing series!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonical Landscape Review</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/landscape-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 16:49:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/landscape-review/</guid>
      <description>For the past 2 years I’ve relied on Canonical Landscape extensively. In this post I’ll summarize my experience with the platform as well as share some important lessons I learned for anyone running mission-critical applications in which Landscape plays a part of the workflow.
For anyone that isn’t familiar with the software, Landscape is Canonical’s SaaS offer to maintain a fleet of Ubuntu servers. From keeping track of USNs, package and user status, to performance and overall maintenance of the servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Recommendation 📹 Solace</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/movie-solace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 22:06:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/movie-solace/</guid>
      <description>Solace
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Recommendation 📹 The Report</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/movie-the-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 22:55:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/movie-the-report/</guid>
      <description>The Report - 2019
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks 🚫 Tools &amp; Productivity ✅</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/life-after-socials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 13:33:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/life-after-socials/</guid>
      <description>Recently I decided it was time to not only take a break but instead fully departure social networks. This is a process that started years ago when I first got rid of other social media services, even though it was only completed when the last standing social network profile came to an end:
The time has come for my last social network presence (Twitter) to come to an end.
Stay safe out there and feel free to reach out to me at tiago @3CORESec ✉️</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Guardduty vs IDS</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/guardduty-vs-ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 13:52:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/guardduty-vs-ids/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across an AWS Blog post titled New third-party test compares Amazon GuardDuty to network intrusion detection systems where the author links to a white paper written by, as the title suggest, a third party.
The intent of their article is to provide an unbiased analyses of the capabilities of AWS GuardDuty when compared with &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; network intrusion detection systems. I do not, however, believe this objective was reached, and I want to highlight a few points about it in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dualcomm ETAP 2003</title>
      <link>https://xroot.org/posts/dualcomm-etap-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 13:55:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xroot.org/posts/dualcomm-etap-2003/</guid>
      <description>The Dualcomm ETAP-2003 is a pretty nifty little device. Because I could not find any images of them before I purchased mine, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a few photos I took:
       </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
